<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on Xliiauo</title>
    <link>https://xliiauo.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on Xliiauo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 12:02:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://xliiauo.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid padding top in Outlook</title>
      <link>https://xliiauo.github.io/post/avoid-padding-top-in-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 12:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xliiauo.github.io/post/avoid-padding-top-in-outlook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I have been organising the team&amp;rsquo;s Brown Bag events since last year, we send out an html email every week to let the team know what&amp;rsquo;s happening. The html email has never been easy to keep a consistent style across all platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The macOS Outlook and the built in Mail has always been very friendly towards html emails. When it comes to the Outlook on Windows and Outlook.com, it is a totally different story. I often find myself spending hours fixing rendering errors on one or the other platform. As my wider team is windows based with some people processing their emails on Outlook.com. I can give up neither of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I finnaly updated our email processing stack to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foundation for email 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Sass version. Which makes my life a little bit easier with its built-in inliner. And the new template makes it easier to use more natural fonts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this time, I was stuck with the Outlook 2010 on Windows. The top header&amp;rsquo;s padding was totally missing. This in the end turned out to be an Outlook bug. The &lt;code&gt;padding-top&lt;/code&gt; will not render properly in certain versions of Outlook and replacing with &lt;code&gt;margin-top&lt;/code&gt; fixed my error. There are also some other things to watch out for. I was trying to create a fansy gradient header bar which worked great on Mac but looked terrible on Outlook for Windows and Outlook.com. The colour was missing and replaced with white. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting the gradient to be rendered correctly but I did put the defualt background colour and seems Outlook just ignored it. After googled a while and I found the &lt;code&gt;bgcolor&lt;/code&gt; attribute came to rescue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related code snips attached:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// In your template sass
.header {
  background: $primary-color;
  background: $primary-gradient;
  background: $primary-gradient-o;
  background: $primary-gradient-moz;
  background: $primary-gradient-webkit;
  filter: $primary-filter;
}

// In the sass where you define your colours
$primary-color: #55379b;
$primary-gradient: linear-gradient(135deg, #55379b, #bdabc4);
$primary-gradient-o: -o-linear-gradient(135deg, #bdabc4, #55379b);
$primary-gradient-moz: -moz-linear-gradient(135deg, #bdabc4, #55379b);
$primary-gradient-webkit: -webkit-linear-gradient(135deg, #bdabc4, #55379b);
$primary-filter: progid:DXImageTransform.Microsoft.gradient(startColorstr=&#39;#55379b&#39;, endColorstr=&#39;#bdabc4&#39;, GradientType=1);

// In your html, add the bgcolor
&amp;lt;wrapper class=&amp;quot;header&amp;quot; bgcolor=&amp;quot;#55379b&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xiao&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world</title>
      <link>https://xliiauo.github.io/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 15:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xliiauo.github.io/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After having tried out several static site engines and hosting solutions. I&amp;rsquo;ve finally started writing my first blog. Yeah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What to write about? I guess everything about my life maybe food or travel? I would probably write a little about technologies although I am really not a guru. I enjoy exploring new technologies and I can spend my whole weekend in my uni library, play with some cool stuff, say, Elasticsearch stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having been in the UK for 2 years and really enjoying living and working here. I found the food is really not too bad. Three of my favourites: sausage rolls, Yorkshire puddings and victoria sponge cakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, guess that is so much for today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xiao&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>